wkhealth.com 2019-12-08

# Privacy & Cookies

**Privacy and Cookie Policy**

Welcome to the Corporate website of Wolters Kluwer. Wolters Kluwer is a global company with multiple offices. This site is owned by Wolters Kluwer NV. This Privacy statement and Cookie Policy (the “Policy”) is applicable to visitors of our website and describes how we collect, use, and disclose personal information of these visitors.

**What information do we collect about you?**

Like many web sites, this site actively collects information from its visitors both by asking you specific questions and by permitting you to communicate directly with us via e-mail. Some of the information that you submit may be personal information (information that uniquely identifies you, such as your name, address, e-mail address, phone number etc.).

Some areas of this site may require you to submit information, to benefit from the specified features (such as e-mail alerts or newsletter subscriptions). You will be informed at each information collection point what information is required and what for.

As you navigate through the website, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies and means, such as cookies (see below), tags, pixels, and navigational data collection.

**How will we use the information about you?**

Wolters Kluwer will use personal information that is collected through this website, to improve our website and manage its performance. Except as otherwise stated, we may use your information to improve the content of our site, to customize the site to your preferences, to communicate information to you (if you have requested it), for our marketing and research purposes, and for the purposes specified in this Policy. We will only disclose your personal information if required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations.

If you subscribe to our e-mail alerts, we collect your e-mail address. This address will only be used for keeping you informed as indicated. If you wish to unsubscribe from our e-mail alert list, you can do so at any moment as indicated in every subscribed e-mail you receive.

To keep your personal data accurate, current, and complete, please contact us in case of any incorrect information at [info@wolterskluwer.com](mailto:info@wolterskluwer.com). We will update or correct personal information that you have previously submitted via this site.

If you are not content with the way Wolters Kluwer is handling your personal information, you have the right under the European General Data Protection Regulation to lodge a complaint with your supervisory authority; see this [list](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080) for applicable authorities.

**Security**

We take reasonable steps to protect your personal information as you transmit your information from your computer to our site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Wolters Kluwer takes the security of personal information seriously and we use appropriate technologies and procedures to protect personal information (including administrative, technical and physical safeguards) according to the risk level and the service provided. 

**Marketing activities**

Wolters Kluwer will use personal information that is collected via this site for marketing purposes.

**Cookies**

This website uses “cookies”. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer, tablet, phone or other endpoint, when you visit a website that helps the site remember information about you and your preferences.

Some cookies are deleted when you exit your browser. These are known as session cookies. Others remain on your device until they expire or you delete them from your cache. These are known as persistent cookies and enable us to remember things about you as a returning visitor.

We may use **Session Cookies** for the following purposes:

  * To allow you to carry information across pages of our website and avoid having to re-enter information.
  * Within registration to allow you to access stored information.
  * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our website and to help us improve the structure of our website.  

**Persistent Cookies** may be used for the following purposes:

  * To help us recognize you as a unique visitor (just a number) when you return to our website and to allow us to tailor content to match your preferred interests.
  * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our website and to help us improve the structure of our website.
  * To internally identify you by account name, email address, customer ID, and location (geographic and IP address).
  * To tailor content to your preferences.

Third-Parties may serve cookies via this website. These **Third-Party Cookies** can be used for the following purposes:

  * To serve content on our site and track whether this content is clicked on by users. 
  * To control how often you are shown specific content. 
  * To count the number of anonymous users of our site, for website usage analysis.

You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to block the placing of cookies at all, but you should realize that this can limit the use of our website or services.

This web site standard uses the following three cookies. The cookies **_ga** and **_gid** record a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website. The cookie **_gat** is used to throttle the request rate, by limiting the number of requests to our site. The cookies _gat and _gid expire when the session ends (session cookies), while the cookie _ga expires after two years (persistent cookie); however, all of these cookies will expire immediately when you delete them.

In addition, we use Google Analytics to monitor and the use of our website. To that end, we have concluded a data processing agreement with Google, declaring Google as processor, processing data on behalf of Wolters Kluwer. Also, we have masked the final byte of your IP-address, switched off data-sharing, and we are not using Google Analytics in conjunction with any other Google services.

We also use Cookies provided by Facebook and LinkedIn, but only if you consent with this. These Cookies operate in different ways but they are both used in connection with Wolters Kluwer advertising served to a user of the Wolters Kluwer web site on LinkedIn and Facebook, the recognition of such users and the devices used by the user to access LinkedIn, Facebook and the Wolters Kluwer web site. Further information on each Cookie is set out in the table below.

Facebook Pixel | Facebook places this Cookie. It enables Wolters Kluwer to measure, optimize and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook. It enables Wolters Kluwer to see how our users move between devices when accessing the Wolters Kluwer web site and Facebook, to ensure that Wolters Kluwer’s Facebook advertising is seen by our users most likely to be interested in such advertising by analysing which content a user has viewed and interacted with on the Wolters Kluwer web site. The Facebook Pixel cookie is stored until you manually delete it. For further information about the Facebook Pixel please see:  
<https://en-gb.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616>  
---|---  
LinkedIn Insight Tag | The LinkedIn Insight Tag is a piece of lightweight JavaScript code that we have added to our websites to enable in-depth campaign reporting and to help us unlock valuable insights about our website visitors. We use the LinkedIn Insight Tag to track conversions, retarget website visitors, and unlock additional insights about members interacting with our LinkedIn adverts.  
The LinkedIn Insight Tag enables the collection of metadata such as IP address information, timestamp, and events such as page views. All data is encrypted. The LinkedIn browser cookie is stored until you manually delete it or when the cookie expires (there’s a rolling six-month expiration from the last time the visitor’s browser loaded the Insight Tag).  
  
Your use of third party web sites and platforms such as LinkedIn and Facebook, and the privacy practices of these platforms, are governed by separate terms, conditions and policies for which Wolters Kluwer is not responsible. You should review LinkedIn’s and Facebook’s terms, conditions and policies where you will find more details on how information about you is used on their platforms and how you can set your privacy preferences.   

**Other websites**

This website may include links to other websites such as Wolters Kluwer products and services. Please note that the Policy is only applicable to this website.  

**International data transfer**

Wolters Kluwer is a global organization which uses networks, servers and databases around the world. The data transfers may vary from time to time pending contractors and include the Netherlands. We have measures in place to ensure that when your personal information is transferred internationally is subject to appropriate safeguards in accordance with data privacy law.

**Your rights**

We will honor your rights under local applicable data privacy laws. Under the European General Data Protection Regulation, you will have the following rights, and may have similar rights under other local applicable data privacy laws:

  * the right to access your personal information: the right to submit a request for details about your personal information or a copy of that personal information
  * the right to rectify your personal information: the right to have inaccurate information about you corrected or removed
  * the right to erase your personal information: the right to have certain personal information about you erased
  * the right to restriction of processing: the right to request that your personal information is only used for restricted purposes
  * the right to data portability: the right to receive the personal information and to transmit this information to another party
  * the right to object: the right to object to processing of your personal information if we informed you that the processing is necessary for our or a third party’s legitimate interests
  * the right to opt out of marketing activities: you can manage your marketing preferences by unsubscribe links found in the communications you receive from us

In response to a request, we will ask you to verify your identity when necessary, and to provide information that helps us to understand your request better. If we do not comply with your request, whether in whole or in part, we will explain why. If you wish to exercise your rights as a data subject, please contact us at [info@wolterskluwer.com](mailto:info@wolterskluwer.com).

**Changes to this Policy**

This Policy may be subject to updates. Please consult this Policy regularly to remain up-to-date. The Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018.

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions, comments, complaints, suggestions, or any other concerns about the way in which we process information about you, please contact our Corporate Privacy office at [privacyoffice@wolterskluwer.com](mailto:privacyoffice@wolterskluwer.com).
